Brian E. Davis

1536 West Davis Street, Burlington, NC 27215 USA 001 (336) 684-9879 | tvc15@mac.com http://www.tvc15media.com

Visual materials archivist and digital production developer applying expertise in collections management, standards-based digitization, and web/iOS development to open digital access across a variety of collection materials. Previous work as collections curator, digitization technician, and digital services librarian, provides experience from a variety of vantage points from within an academic library.

Core Competencies:

- Visual Materials Digitization
- Moving Image Digitization
- Nonlinear Video Editing
- **Archival Processing**
- Collections Development
- Digital Project Planning
- Technical & Descriptive Metadata

 Scripting Languages

 Digital Object Validation

 Scripting Languages

 LAMP Server Admin
- iOS Development
- Web Development

Professional Experience

Media & Digital Services Librarian, High Point University Libraries, High Point, NC

4/2009 - Current

- Providing software training for faculty, staff, and students in the instructional media lab
- Development and maintenance of circulating/instructional DVD collections
- Development of library and university iOS/iPhone applications
- Processing and preservation of archival visual materials holdings
- Conducting and/or coordinating conservation work on archives materials
- Development of digital collections publishing platform
- Providing moving image reformatting and digitization services
- Web and new media development for HPU Libraries
- Production of instructional and promotional library video tutorials
- Providing University-wide audiovisual tech support
- Providing web statistics and lab usage statistics
- Staff and student aide supervision

Digital Production Developer, Duke University Libraries, Durham, NC

1/2008 - 11/2008

- Creating digital images from a variety of special collections/archives source materials
- Establishment of moving image reformatting and digitization services
- Conducting tests to establish settings and benchmarks for digitization projects
- Assisting in Digital Collections Program project planning

- Identifying potential conservation issues with library materials
- · Providing consultation on digital imaging methods to project sponsors
- Developing standards, policies, procedures, and documentation for digitization lab operations
- Building and maintaining databases to manage projects and record technical metadata
- Training and supervising of digitization staff and quality control operators
- Establishment of JHOVE digital image validation to digitization workflow
- Development of self-describing image workflow
- Providing digital production statistics

Academic Associate for Media Development, Arizona State University Libraries, Tempe, AZ

12/2005 - 1/2008

- Establishment of moving image reformatting and digitization services
- Establish guidelines and supervise departmental photographic digitization services
- Acquisition of new photographic and moving image archival collections
- Processing and preservation of visual material holdings (photographic & moving image)
- Provide specialized photographic and moving image materials reference
- Provide general reference desk service in the Luhrs Reading Room
- Conduct and/or coordinate conservation work on collection materials
- Archival collections record management (CONTENTdm, PBCore, EAD, & MARC)
- Assist in the development of digital audio, digital video, and multimedia projects
- Flash animation development for ASU Libraries
- Staff and student aide supervision

Education

Master of Science in Graphic Information Technology

College of Technology and Innovation

Arizona State University

2007

Bachelor of Arts in Art History

College of Arts and Sciences
University of Tennessee
2002

Professional Affiliations

Association of Moving Image Archivists, Member since 2005.

Society of American Archivists, Member since 2006.

Publications, Citations, and Quotations

Davis, Brian E. *Guardian of the Flame Sri Lanka Manuscripts Collection*, in Philip N. Cronenwett, Osborn, Kevin and Samuel A. Streit. 2007. Celebrating Research: Rare and Special Collections from the Membership of the Association of Research Libraries, Washington DC: Association of Research Libraries.

<u>Arizona Stories: The Schwemberger Collection</u>. Arizona Stories. Television program. Tempe, AZ: KAET-TV, July 31, 2007.

Gabrielson, Ryan. 2006. *New View of History Uncovered at ASU*. East Valley Tribune, July 29: 16-19.

Smith, Judith. 2006. Lost and found: Archivists Unveil Footage of WWII Relocation Center, ASU Insight, July 21:4.

Prewitt, Deborah. 2006. *Study: Consumers Accept Personalization Technology*, ASU Insight, April 7:3.

Smith, Judith. 2006. Lost and found: Archivists Unveil Footage of WWII Relocation Center, ASU Magazine, 10(3):7.

Taylor, Robert D., editor. 2005. *The Schwemberger Photographs: An Acquisition from the Franciscan Southwest Mission*, Phoenix: Arizona State University.

Abe-Harris, La Verne, Deborah Baney, Brian E. Davis, and Howard Nelson. 2005. *The Personalization of Data for Web Site and Print Publishers*. Electronic Document Systems Foundation, http://www.edsf.org/what we do/research/academic research.html.

Presentations

Lost and found: Archivists Unveil Footage of WWII Relocation Center, Co-presenter, Arizona Board of Regents (ABOR), Tempe AZ, June 2006.

A Celebration of the Human Spirit: Japanese-American Relocation Camps in Arizona, Copresenter, Arizona Historical Foundation, Tempe AZ, May 2006.

Continuing Education and Professional Development

Apple Pro Certification Program
Final Cut Studio (FCS) Master Certification
In progress
http://www.apple.com/software/pro/training/
Winston Salem, NC

Academy of Certified Archivists

Archival Certification Program In progress http://www.certifiedarchivists.org Albany, NY

Glass Plate Negative Conservation Workshop Arizona State University Libraries 2007 Tempe, AZ

OCLC Western Service Center

Audio/Video Materials: Preserving and Managing Collections Workshop

2007

http://www.oclc.org/western/default.htm

Lacey, WA

Digital Imaging Workshop with William Comstock (HCL) Arizona State University Libraries 2006 Tempe, AZ

Microcomputers in Education Conference Final Cut Express Digital Video Workshop 2005

http://mec.asu.edu/2005

Tempe, AZ

Service

Chair, Film and Video Collections Development Committee, High Point University Libraries, 2010.

Chair, Web Development Committee, High Point University Libraries, 2010.

Co-chair, Moving Image Digitization Working Group, Duke University Libraries, 2008.

Member, Digital Collections Working Group, Duke University Libraries, 2008.

Member, Digital Collections Implementation Group, Duke University Libraries, 2008.

Member, Video Content and fedora Working Group, Arizona State University Libraries, 2007.

Member, *Imaging Standards for Digital Still Images Working Group*, Arizona State University Libraries, 2006.

Member, Image Catalog Environment Working Group, Arizona State University Libraries, 2006.

Technical Proficiencies

Platforms: Mac OS, MS Windows, Linux, MySQL, Oracle, iOS,

Web Languages: HTML, HTML5, XHTML, PHP, CSS3, JavaScript, Objective-C

Media Software: Photoshop, Dreamweaver, Flash, Illustrator, Final Cut Studio, Maya,

JHOVE, Capture One, SAMMA Eye, QuickTime Pro, Color, Bridge,

MAGpie

Library Software: SirsiDynix Workflows, CONTENTdm, Gallery Systems TMS, Omeka,

Archivists' Toolkit, PBCore, Millennium ILS

Metadata Standards: MIX, METS, MODS, EAD, MARC 21, Dublin Core, OAI-PMH, MPEG-7